(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
言の葉を紡いで
Spinning the words,
微睡んだ泡沫
a drowsy bubble...
旅人迷いこむ
A traveler wanders into
御伽の深い霧
the deep fog of a fairy tale.
差し伸べた掌
The palm I reached out,
そっと触れる予感
a premonition of gently touching.
受け止めて零れた
Caught and spilled,
光の一滴
a single drop of light.
面影虚ろって
The image fades,
微笑んだ幻
a smiling phantom.
想いの果てる場所
The place where my feelings end
まだ遥か遠くて
is still far away.
求め探して 彷徨って やがて詠われて
Seeking, searching, wandering, and eventually sung,
幾千幾万幾億の旋律となる
becoming billions of melodies.
いつか失い奪われて 消える運命でも
Even if it is fated to be lost and disappear,
それは忘れられる事なき物語
that is a story that will never be forgotten.
指先を絡めて
Intertwining our fingertips,
触れる誰かの夢
touching someone's dream.
刻まれた想いの
Of the feelings carved,
鼓動だけが響く
only the heartbeat echoes.
言の葉を紡いで微睡んだ泡沫
Spinning words, I slumbered in a bubble
旅人迷い込む御伽の深い霧
A traveler wanders into the deep mist of a fairy tale
求め探して彷徨ってやがて詠われて
Seeking, searching, wandering, and finally being sung
いつか失い奪われて消える運命でも
Even if it is our fate to one day be lost or taken
それは忘れられることなくここにある
It will remain here without ever being forgotten
求め探して彷徨ってやがて詠われて
Seeking, searching, wandering, and finally being sung
幾千幾万幾億の旋律となる
Becoming millions of melodies
ようこそお越しなさったご主人様
Welcome, Master
隣に座ってせーの
Sit next to me, and... one, two!
萌 萌 萌 萌
Moe Moe Moe Moe
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ ねぇ教えて
Who's gonna be happy with this? Hey, tell me
笑顔で up, pull, pull
With a smile, up, pull, pull
愛想を忘れてご苦労様
Thanks for the hard work, despite the rudeness
私とあなたでせーの
You and me, and... one, two!
luv luv luv luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ ねぇ教えて
Who's gonna be happy with this? Hey, tell me
笑顔で up, pull, pull
With a smile, up, pull, pull
ひらりはらり 女の子
Fluttering, a girl
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Floating, the lies of words
それでつまりおさめなきゃ 感情的リアル
So in short, I have to keep it in, emotional reality
笑顔で up, pull, pull
With a smile, up, pull, pull
人は見かけによらぬもの
People are not what they seem
嘘を嘘と見抜けない
You can't see through the lies
したたかなその背中 鳥肌寒暖差
That sturdy back, goosebumps from the chill
and drop
欲しかった御指名頂きますわ
I'll take the nomination I wanted
私とあなたでせーの
You and me, and... one, two!
bang bang bang bang
これはど派手にご苦労様
Thanks for your flashy hard work
遊びましょ 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Let's play, with a smile, up, pull, pull
ひらりはらり ここはどこ
Fluttering, where is this?
ふわりふわり so let me show
Floating, so let me show
それでつまりおさめなきゃ 感情的リアル
So in short, I have to keep it in, emotional reality
笑顔で up, pull, pull
With a smile, up, pull, pull
歌い出す 夢の鐘
The bell of dreams begins to sing
終わることのないこの世界
In this never-ending world
悲しいことも 虚しいことも
Both the sad things and the empty things
眠らせて
Let them sleep
Hi! Oh my god! Hello everyone!
It's the ancient weapon from Hololive ID 2nd gen, Anya Melfissa! Hello!
Thank you so much for coming to my 3D Birthday Live! Oh my god, finally!
今日はね、アーニャの誕生日ということで、3D生誕祭ライブへようこそ！
Today is Anya's birthday, so welcome to my 3D Birthday Live!
3D生誕祭ライブです！やったー！
It's my 3D Birthday Live! Yay!
ね、見に来てくれてありがとう、みんな
Hey, thanks for coming to watch, everyone.
Oh my god, I'm so excited! I'm so so excited...
Especially since it's my first 3D birthday live!
Yes, I am so excited, and I've still got a few more songs to sing to you guys!
But first of all, remember to post a lot with this hashtag, #CuriousTune3D.
Remember to post a lot of screenshots and all of your, you know, favorite moments.
このハッシュタグでね、ぜひみんな、いっぱいポストして。後で見るから
Be sure to post a lot with this hashtag, I'll be checking them later.
I'll be checking them out after the live.
Please, please, nya.
I think I like the title a lot. I think I like the title of the 3D birthday live a lot. I think it's pretty unique.
Through the Curious Tune.
Yeah, I really like that title. Sounds pretty unique.
Sounds very Anya-like.
And it sure fits this stage. Look at this! Look at this stage!
Look at this stage! The 3D birthday live stage, isn't it so cool and cute?
It's very cool and cute, oh my god.
ね、このステージめっちゃすごくない？
Hey, isn't this stage amazing?
ここでね、あの、いっぱい歌うの。これからいっぱい歌うんだけど、マジで楽しみ
I'm going to sing a lot here. I'll be singing a lot from now on, and I'm really looking forward to it.
I can't wait to sing a few more songs in this stage after this.
And then, at the end... Oh my god, at the end...
I'll be singing my new original song!
So be sure to watch until the end.
ね、今日はね、最後でなんとオリ曲！
Hey, today, at the end, I have an original song!
新しいオリ曲聴けるかもしれないので、みんなね、最後まで見てね
You might get to hear a new original song, so everyone, watch until the end!
ということで、ここからまだまだ行きますよ
And so, we're still going from here!
まだまだ歌って行きますよ、ゲストさんたちとね
I'll keep on singing, along with my guests!
I'll be singing with some guests, some very, very special guests.
So I hope you guys are as excited as I am! Yippee!
So... Hmm, shall we go to the next song? Shall we go to the next song?
Oh my god, what is it going to be? What's the next song?
次の曲はなんだろうな、行きますかね、次の曲は
I wonder what the next song will be... Shall we go? The next song...
じゃあね、行きましょう。次の曲は...
Alright, let's go. The next song is...
The next song is...
愛包ダンスホール！
Ai-Pai Dance Hall!
愛包ダンスホール
Ai-Pai Dance Hall
今日はボレロ
Today is a bolero
蕩けった少年
A melted boy,
甘酸っぱい感情
bittersweet emotions
求愛人類 満杯
Love-seeking humanity is at full capacity
オーブントースターは漏れ漏れよ
The oven toaster is leaking
おかわりはアンコール次第ね
A second serving depends on the encore
オワラナイ・ラブコール・ノ・ダンス・デ
With an unending love call dance
愛包ダンスホール
Ai-Pai Dance Hall
おかわりならもう欲しい
If it's a second serving, I want it already
愛包ダンスホール
Ai-Pai Dance Hall
3.1415926535のπだって
Even pi, 3.1415926535...
割り切れない気持ち抱えてるよ
Holds onto feelings that can't be divided evenly.
ラブ人も原人もエンジも円陣組んで仲良くやれたらとか
If love-people, primitives, and engines could form a circle...
割り切れない命境のヘヴン
A heaven on the border of life that can't be divided.
今夜はいいんじゃない
Isn't tonight just fine?
踊ればいいんじゃない
Shouldn't we just dance?
柔旋唱舞 唯唱願全 仰宣御前
Soft spin, only wishing for completeness before you
羅寸万堕 羅岸堕羅 散左羅
Ra-sun-man-da, Ra-gan-da-ra, San-sa-ra
なにしてんだ
What are you doing?
高まった感動の再会
A reunion of heightened emotions
集まった愛情のWi-Fi
A Wi-Fi of gathered affection
持ち寄って丁度の人生
A life that's just right when brought together
乱れてるが重なって
Disordered but overlapping
今はゆるゆるの状態
Right now it's a loose, relaxed state
あつあつパイみたいだね
Just like a hot, fresh pie
Bye-bye-bye-bye-bye!
愛・愛・愛でホレホレよ
Falling head over heels with love, love, love!
蕩けった少年 甘酸っぱい感情
A melted boy, bittersweet emotions
求愛人類 満杯
Love-seeking humanity is at full capacity
乾杯交戦にホレホレよ
Falling head over heels in a cheers battle!
ミルキィみたいね 愛よ露に集まれ
Just like milky, let love gather in the dew!
パッパラパッパラパ！
Pa-ppa-ra pa-ppa-ra pa!
なだらかな脳内ノリのジャンルも
Even the genre of the gentle rhythm in the brain,
愛包かい？
is it Heart Pie?
会話しようぜ PPL の祭典
Let's talk, at the festival of people!
ダンスホールじゃ暇人もヒーロー
In the dance hall, even the idle are heroes!
乾杯！今日はボレロ
Cheers! Today is a bolero
持ち寄って人類
Bringing humanity together
叫んじゃって笑わす
Shouting and making them laugh
おかわり欲しいでしょう
You'll want a second serving, right?
全人類恒星 舞踏会の結末的
All humanity's stars, at the end of the ball
一日中レンジしてハイになるような
Microwaving all day long to get high
脳味噌もトロトロのような
The brain feeling all melted too
実感を動画にオンして
Putting that feeling onto a video
踊りまして煩悩 総裁きまして
Dancing through worldly desires, judging them
手順を操作
Manipulating the steps
Bye-bye-bye-bye-bye!
人類最高のダンスタイム
Humanity's best dance time
愛包ダンスホール
Ai-Pai Dance Hall
ラライライ 愛包ダンスホール
La-la-i-lai, Ai-Pai Dance Hall
愛包ダンスホール
Love-Wrapped Dance Hall
僕らが生まれて初めて知る音は
The first sound we learn after we are born...
心臓の鼓動なの？
Is it the beating of our hearts?
タトント タトント タトント タテンタタトンダ
Ta-ton-to, ta-ton-to, ta-ton-to...
それはリズムと知った
I learned that it was rhythm
いにしえも 今どきも
In ancient times and nowadays,
ハイビートが僕らを作って繋いでんだろう
High beats are what make us and connect us, right?
アイ・パイ
Ai-pai
アイ・パイ・愛・パイで オレオレヨ
Ai-pai, Ai-pai, ole, ole, yo!
蕩けっちゃおね 甘酸っぱいレモン 救愛人類パイ満載
Let's melt, bittersweet lemon, love-seeking humanity full of pi
乾杯 完全にホレホレヨ
Cheers! I'm completely in love, love, yo!
見ら見ら見たい愛踊り悪魔ねかパッパラパッパッパ
Look, look, I want to see a love dance... pappara pappa pa!
ラガラララララ
La-ga-la-la-la-la...
まるでラビリンスを踊ってるみたい
it's like dancing through a labyrinth
生まれ変わったような気分でして
Feeling like I've been reborn
乾杯ね 今日はボレロ
Cheers! Today it's a bolero
妄信的バカなんて笑って
Laughing at a blind fool
テレレテテッテテッテ
Te-re-re-te-te-te-te-te
愛おしいよな 終わりは近づけとさ
It's lovely, let the end draw near
終わらないパイのように続きたい
I want to continue like a never-ending pi
計算なんてできないが
I can't even calculate it
アイ・パイ アイ・パイダンスホール 今日はボレロ
Ai-pai, Ai-pai Dance Hall, today it's a bolero
蕩けっちゃおね 甘酸っぱいレモン 救愛人類パイ満載
Let's melt, bittersweet lemon, love-seeking humanity full of pi
また食べに来てね
Please come back to eat again
あなたならいつでもいいよ
For you, anytime is fine
おかわり欲しいでしょ
You want a refill, don't you?
愛包ダンスホール
Love-Wrapped Dance Hall
おかわりならもし
If you want a refill
愛包ダンスホール
Love-Wrapped Dance Hall
どうぞ
Here you go
さよならプリンセス 宙に舞っている
Goodbye princess, fluttering in the air
眠り沈むその姿は華やかな
Sleeping, sinking, your figure is glamorous
魅惑のハッピーエンド 私とさよならだ
An enchanting happy ending, it's goodbye to me
鏡の中独り縛られて
Tied up alone in the mirror
頭の中逃げ回る毎日です
My head is running around every day
ずっと ずっと だって私変われないし
Always, always, 'cause I can't change
夢もないし 口もないし つまらないし
And I have no dreams, no mouth, boring
可愛くもないし 分からないし 仕方ないし
Not even cute, I don't know, I can't help it
不意に気づいたらまるで
Suddenly I noticed
指輪が首輪になっていたんだ
The ring had become a collar
壊れた大人の愛情なんだ
It's the distorted affection of an adult
期待をかけて
Pinning your hopes on me...
私のことなんて気にしないでね
just don't mind me
さよならプリンセス 宙に舞っている
Goodbye princess, fluttering in the air
独り浮かぶその姿は華やかな
Floating alone, your figure is glamorous
魅惑のハッピーエンド 私とさよならだ
An enchanting happy ending, it's goodbye to me
間抜けなプリンセス 過去とバイバイだ
Stupid princess, say bye-bye to the past
この際ね何もかもを燃やしてしまおう
At this point, let's burn everything down
このまま宙を泳いであの星になれたら
If only I could swim through the air and become that star
私 私とさよならだ
Goodbye to me, to myself
心を洗え 妬み渦巻いた
Wash your heart, jealousy swirls...
体の中から空回り毎日です
My body is spinning in vain every day
ずっと ずっと だってあなた頭いいし
Always, always, 'cause you are smart
変わらないし 足長いし 面白いし
And you don't change, you have long legs, you're funny
顔も可愛いし さりげないし 仕方ないし
Your face is cute, you're nonchalant, I can't help it
溢れるオーラはまるで
Your overflowing aura is like...
キラキラ輝く安定剤ね
a sparkling stabilizer
めろめろ私も面目ないね
I'm head over heels, I'm so ashamed
古い息の私のことなんて
The old version of me...
探さないでね
don't come looking for her
さよならプリンセス 愛に酔っている
Goodbye princess, drunk on love
独り浮かぶその姿は鮮やかな
Floating alone, your figure is vivid
理想のハッピーエンド 私とさよならだ
An ideal happy ending, it's goodbye to me
さよならプリンセス 全てバイバイだ
Goodbye princess, say bye-bye to everything
巡り巡る幸せに絡まるほど
As much as I get entangled in the revolving happiness
間抜けなハッピーエンド 可愛くなれたかな
A stupid happy ending, did I become cute?
私 私はすでに分かっていたんだ
I, I already knew it
これでさよならか
Is this goodbye?
ちょっと どうもこうも 煮え切らない とっちらかっちゃって まとまらない
You know what? I just can't make up my mind. It's so messed up...
ひとりぼっちの世界に響く モノローグ
The monologue echoes in this lonely world.
あれもこれも できやしない？ 回る回るメリーゴーランド
Is it impossible for me to do this and that? The merry-go-round goes round.
ぐだって うだって いくほど 持て余すハングリー
The more I mess around and waste time, the more I become hungry.
あっちこっち 進んで止まって 独りよがり
Moving back and forth, getting stuck, all by myself.
どん詰まりでも諦めない 駆けろスターダム
Even in a dead end, I won't give up, run towards stardom!
ならひとりぼっちじゃつまらないでしょ
Then, being all alone must be boring, right?
有象無象も全て あの星を目指せ
Everyone, every one of you, aim for that star!
まるで掴みやしない 届きやしない 願いもしまって
Even the wishes that can't be grasped, keep them safe.
銀河を駆けてゆく
Sprinting through the galaxy
星座のボレロを踊り語る
Dancing and narrating a bolero of constellations
恐れはしない
I won't be afraid
怯みもしない
I won't flinch
呆れるほどに
To an astounding degree
無謀な愉快な冒険さ
It's a reckless and fun adventure
止まらないまま
Without stopping...
It's Showtime!!
ねえ待って待って
Hey, wait, wait!
おかしいな
That's strange...
次のセリフが
The next line...
噛んじゃった
I messed it up
迷い子になった世界に降りる
Descending into a world where I've become a lost child
エン・ド・ロール
End roll
何て？
What?
どうしてやるせない？
Why is it so helpless?
不安残る午後
An afternoon with lingering anxiety
噛み付いて吐き巻くフレーム
A frame that bites and spits out
苦くてたまらない
It's so bitter I can't stand it
愛故のファンタズマ
A phantasm born of love
悩んで遠回り
Worrying and taking detours
空回り
Running in circles
固定観念なんて壊してこそ
Only by breaking through fixed concepts...
最高のショータイム
can we have the best showtime
なら聴き飽きて真っ赤に味気ないだろう
Then you'll get tired of hearing it and find it dull
エンジン全開 Go Go 絶好調スター
Engine full throttle, go go, a star in top form
わがままに持て成そうか
Shall we entertain you selfishly?
高いとこと低いとこで ババババンッて
With high parts and low parts... boom boom boom.
確かに 確かに
True, true.
低いとこばっかだったよ私
I was mostly doing the low parts.
あるよね でもかっこよかったですよ
Right? But it was so cool!
まろろーん…とかね あんな低いの出したことないよ
Like 'maroro-n'... I've never made a voice that low!
イケボIRyS珍しいからさ たまにはいいんじゃないかな
Ikebo IRyS is rare, so isn't it good once in a while?
まあ確かにね こういうイケボIRyS レアなんでね
Well, true. This kind of Ikebo IRyS is rare.
8歳だもんね
Since she's 8 years old.
8歳なのにね！
Even though I'm 8!
8歳のイケボ？ もう、もう！ それはそれ
An 8-year-old's Ikebo? Geez! That's that.
みんな受け取ってね IRySのかっこよさを
Everyone, accept it. IRyS's coolness.
てへ、8歳 ごめん
Hehe, 8 years old. Sorry.
絶対この後アーカイブ見返して
Definitely check the archive later.
やだ 見たくない！
No, I don't want to see it!
見返して！ 見てほしい！
Watch it! I want you to see!
あにゃのライブはちゃんと見てね
Watch Anya's live, but...
この部分だけ飛ばして
...skip just this part.
一番大事なとこでしょ！
That's the most important part!
めっちゃ喉渇いたな
My throat is so dry.
あら 喉渇いた？
Oh, is your throat dry?
急に喉渇いたね このテンションで
Suddenly dry? With this tension.
喉渇いたな… あらあら お飲み物ないかな？
My throat is dry... oh my... isn't there something to drink?
あ！ なんか来た！ なんか出てきたよ
Ah! Something's coming! Something's appeared!
あにゃちゃーん！ たくさん歌って喉渇いたでしょ！
Anya-chan! You sang a lot, so you must be dry!
そうだよ！
That's right!
これ飲んでほしいのら
I want you to drink this.
何その声？ 怪しい 怪しい…
What's with that voice? Suspicious, suspicious...
なんかこぼしてる！
She's spilling something!
はい これは…
Here, this is...
怪しいな… 熱っ！ これ何？ 湯気立ってる 熱っ！
Suspicious... hot! What is this? Steam is rising, so hot!
熱そう！ うんとしごく熱いもの 飲んで飲んで！
Looks hot! Something very hot, drink it, drink it!
まあ 一旦飲むか
Well, I'll drink it for now.
本当に飲んだ！ すごい 一気飲み？
She really drank it! Wow, in one go?
ふぅ… めっちゃ めっちゃ美味しかったよでも
Phew... but it was really, really delicious.
ホント？ 怪しかったけど めっちゃ美味しかった？
Really? It was suspicious, but really delicious?
よかった
Good.
うわぁぁ！ 何これ？！
Whoa! What's this?!
ちょっと待って あにゃ？！ どういうこと？！
Wait, Anya?! What do you mean?!
でっけぇぇ！
You're huge!
あんまり動き回らないでよ！ 足元注意！
Don't move around too much! Watch your step!
すごーい！ でかくなったんだけど！
Amazing! She got so big!
すごい揺れるんだけど！ これ潰れるな
It's shaking so much! They'll get crushed...
みんな みんな潰れるんじゃない？ ちょっとやめてよ！
Everyone, won't everyone get crushed? Stop it!
神！ はい！ あぁぁ！
God! Yes! Aaaaah!
アイリスー！ 残りは二人！
IRyS! Two left!
ルーナ先輩 元に戻してくださいよ！
Luna-senpai, please turn her back!
じゃないと潰れちゃうぞ！
Or we'll be crushed!
もしかしたらお茶かければ元に戻るかも？
Maybe if I pour tea on her she'll go back?
暴力 暴力反対！
Violence! I'm against violence!
それだ！ やってよルーナ！ 頼む！
That's it! Do it Luna! Please!
足元にかけてみるのら 普通にかけるんですか
I'll try pouring it on her feet. Just normally?
ジョボジョボジョボ...
Dojo dojo dojo...
おぉ？！ え？！ ちっちゃい！
Oh?! Eh?! Small!
さっきよりもちっちゃくなっちゃった！
She got even smaller than before!
ルーナ先輩 どういう飲み物なんですかそれ！
Luna-senpai, what kind of drink is that?!
小さくなったならね… そんなことはどうだっていいんだよ
If you got smaller... That doesn't matter now!
あにゃ あにゃ ちっちゃい！
Anya, Anya, so tiny!
可愛いね！ 妖精みたいだよ！
Cute! Like a fairy!
小さーい！ 出た出た出た ひどいことしないでよ！
So small! There it is. Don't do anything mean!
可愛いから ご褒美あげちゃう
Since you're cute, I'll give you a reward.
え どういうご褒美？ あにゃちゃん
Eh, what kind of reward? Anya-chan...
おらぁぁ！ それは… それは…
Oryah! That... that...
アイリスの足が… ぱんつらと見せかけて…
IRyS's legs... looks like a pantsu-shot...
ババババン！ 何て 残酷な…
Boom boom boom! How cruel...
痛い 痛い！ ちょっと2メートルがやることじゃないよ！
Ouch, ouch! That's not something a 2-meter-tall person should do!
あにゃが2メートルだと思いますー？
Do you think Anya is 2 meters tall?
2センチだよ こんなにちっちゃくて可愛いから
You're 2 centimeters because you're so tiny and cute.
確かに 2センチだね
True, 2 centimeters.
あにゃにプレゼントもあげたことだし そろそろ帰ろっか
Since we gave Anya a present, it's about time to head back.
時間だし じゃあね！
It's time, bye!
元に戻してくださいよその前に！ 元に戻してくださいよー！
Turn me back before that! Turn me back!
ちょっと待ってー！
Wait!
響かせていく
Let it resonate
The party's over
お芝居はお終い
The play is finished
止まらない We get it, we get it go
I can't stop, We get it, we get it go
導いて頂戴...
Lead me on...
Don't cry
あたらしい今も 気後れないように創るから
I'll create the new now so I won't feel left behind
必ず追い付いて見せるから
I'll show you I can definitely catch up
兎角今迄
Anyway, until now
正しいことは与えられてた
The right things were given to us
送り足を送れたのは
The one who sent me off...
君だけ
Was only you
愛していたい
I want to keep loving you
歌い出さなきゃ始まらない
It won't start unless we start singing
いびつなステップでもいい 今は君と踊っていたい
Even if it's an awkward step, right now I want to dance with you
ただ 生きるためのまじないを そこに残したんだ
I left a spell there just for the sake of living
命を追ってほしい 君と短く長い季節を辿っていたい
I want you to chase life, I want to trace the short and long seasons with you
Night-night party's over 初めまして
Night-night, the party's over, nice to meet you
ヴェール
Veil
どうしても聞き流して
No matter what, please ignore it
その深い深い憂鬱に
In that deep, deep melancholy...
別の色を載せちゃい
I want to overlay another color.
おいたしたから振りも今蹴飛ばして
Because I've kicked away the past...
駆けつけるから
and I'm rushing to you now.
甘く見守って見せるから
Because I'll show you I can watch over you sweetly
bye-bye してもう
Even if we say goodbye...
元通りにだなんてない
we'll never go back to the way things were.
私に成せることはないが
There's nothing I can achieve, but...
でもそうだきっと
But that's right, surely...
祝う空に舞って言って
dance in the celebratory sky and say it.
仰ぐ頷き 広がる空から
Looking up, nodding, from the spreading sky
合図していたい うっかりしなきゃ始まらない
I want to be signaling, it won't start unless I'm careless
歪なステップでも 今は君と踊っていたい
Even with distorted steps, right now I want to dance with you
ただ生きるための まじないを そこに残したい
I want to leave a spell there, just for the sake of living
命を追って欲しい 君と
I want you to chase after life...
短く長い季節を歩って
walking through short and long seasons with you.
bye-bye してもう 元通りにだなんてない
Even if we say goodbye, we'll never go back to the way things were
私に出来ることはあるか
Is there anything I can do?
このテンポ そうだ こんな歌なら どうだ
This tempo, that's right, if it's a song like this, how about it?
だらしなくないけど ちょっといいかもね
It's not slovenly, but it might be a little good
もっと響かせて
Make it resonate more
この道に駆けて
Running through this path
ずうっといっしょ!
Always Together!
充電器を貸して！
Lend me a charger!
またあなたのせいであたしすり減った
Again, because of you, I'm worn out
終電見逃してまたあたしのせいで帰れなくなった
Missed the last train, again because of me I can't go home
繋がっていようね、消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, bring it to a war of attrition
破廉恥な思い出で
In the shameful memories...
ずうっといっしょ！
let's stay together forever!
参観日にだって誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
Even on visiting day, I felt like no one was watching me
散々シニカって昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
I became cynical and stopped expecting anything from the city by day
そうやって守った孤独さえ めちゃくちゃになった
Even the loneliness I protected like that became a mess
あたしいつだって 死にたくて仕方ない
I've always been desperate to die
こんな顔 だいじにしたいと思えないもん
I can't even think of holding this face dear
ともに過ごした日々が
The days we spent together...
ささやかな幸せが
the modest happiness...
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
if only they could become an irreplaceable trauma.
あんなレパートリーなんて 誰かが付け足す 束の間だよね
That kind of repertory is just a fleeting moment someone adds, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll be with you as your lifelong regret
大切なものってなに？ 今失くしたそれ
What's the most important thing? The one you just lost
私と間違いを犯したんな 取り返しがつかないです
I've made a mistake with you, it's irreversible
声が枯れる時も 止める時も
When my voice withers, when I stop it...
狂い咲きの中でずうっといっしょ
in the midst of blooming madness, let's stay together.
もうちょっと普通に 悲しいこと 悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to think of sad things as sad, a little more normally
絶頂の最中に 感情一掃して 楽になりたかった
In the midst of the climax, I wanted to clear my emotions and be at ease
先生 一生懸命に 生きてくださいね
Teacher, please live with all your might
あたしいつだって 死にたくて仕方ない
I've always been desperate to die
あんな奴の言いなりになんていたくないの
I don't want to be at the mercy of someone like that
あなただけ一人で 私の目を盗んで
Don't think of becoming happy by stealing my eyes...
幸せになろうなんて思わないで
all by yourself.
髪を乾かしてくれる指から
From the fingers that dry my hair...
私は壊されたんだよ
I was destroyed.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll be with you as your lifelong regret
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that has become impossible to remove
ずっと欲しがっている 最低だよ
Always wanting it, it's the worst
一緒にいた時の方が 私可愛かったな
When we were together, I was cuter
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll be with you as your lifelong regret
大切なものってなに？ 胸失くしたそれ
What's the most important thing? The one I lost in my heart
私と間違いを犯したんな 取り返しがつかないです
I've made a mistake with you, it's irreversible
声が枯れる時も 止める時も
When my voice withers, when I stop it...
誰かと眠っていても
even if you're sleeping with someone else...
朝が来るまでずうっといっしょ
let's stay together forever until morning comes.
排気に酔ったケーデンス
Cadence drunk in pollution
もう嫌なこと全部投げ出して
Let's abandon everything you hate
斯く濁った正義を疑って
And question the murky justice
あなたの話は退屈で
Your stories are boring
悪魔だの所為で
Because of those devils
生まれた地位が悪かった所為で
Because the status I was born into was bad
全部あなたの所為で
It's all because of you
評価差を持ってくるの忘れた
I forgot to bring the assessment
興味ないそんなトピック
I'm not interested in such topics
嘘吐き妖精に最期 ありがたく終焉に愛を
To the lying fairy, finally, love the end thankfully
ヘルメット姿見終わった夜だ
The night I finished watching the helmet's figure
サウンドがスリンク合ったミッション
The sound synchronized with the mission
冷明の職場見上げな
Look up at the workplace of the dawn
反旗を求めて
Seeking rebellion
もう嫌なこと全部投げ出したいで
Wanting to abandon everything I hate
愛想を解いてクレイジー
Undo the politeness, it's crazy
教唆を持ってくるの忘れた
I forgot to bring the incitement
掛け替えのないボキャ
Irreplaceable vocab
みたいなつまらなくなった幻想 結局神が怖いの
Like those boring illusions, in the end I'm afraid of God
液晶をずっと領主なんだ
The LCD is the lord all along
どんな未来を勝者に選んで
Whatever future is chosen for the winner
誰が生贄になるかな
I wonder who will be the sacrifice
躍るドールを視
Watching the dancing doll
神戸垂れて乞い
Bowing my head and begging
会食もなく垂れ永劫の過食と寄り添いながら
With no dinner, leaning on eternal overeating
ついに見たり
Finally seen
街を開けた海
The sea that opened the town
穿たれた服従
The pierced obedience
汚れた市場の最下の歴史に
In the lowest history of the dirty market
目覚めた星は輝く後光
The awakened star is a shining halo
ドクター・キドリです
I'm Dr. Pretender
愛・爆破ッテロ
Here to bomb you with love
簡単になれば
If it's something that simple
埋まった　マター　マター
It's been buried, matter, matter
ドクター・キドリです
I'm Dr. Pretender
愛想良いかも
Maybe I'm friendly
朦朧　オオトも
Hazy, Ooto too
埋めた　メタ　メタ
Buried, meta, meta
どこにもないから寝ていたら
I couldn't find it anywhere, so while sleeping
壊れて泣いてる夢を診たんだよ
I examined a dream that was broken and crying
治験
Clinical trial
には嘘に身を窶してくる
Disguising myself in lies
顔が解けちゃいそうだよ
My face feels like it's going to melt away
見せ掛け権利を奪ったんだ
I stole the right to pretend
無くして欲しい本能を
The instinct I want to lose
どうやら生き延びてしまったんだ
It seems I've survived
味も解けちゃいそうだよ
The taste feels like it's going to melt away
嘘が解けちゃったんだ
The lie has melted away
嘘が手欲しい本能を
The instinct that wants lies
どうやら欲したと思ったんだ
I thought I wanted it
ドクター・キドリです
I'm Dr. Pretender
本番やめるよ
I'll stop the real show
足し行く感動モニターも
Even the growing emotional monitors
トクとくの毒だけ
Only the specialized poison
回す　ワタ　ワタ
Spinning, wata, wata
顔が解けちゃいそうだよ
My face feels like it's going to melt away
見せ掛け権利を奪ったんだ
I stole the right to pretend
無くなっちゃ欲しい本能を
The instinct I want to disappear
どうやら生き延びてしまったんだ
It seems I've survived
ドクター・キドリになってしまう
Becoming Dr. Pretender
人が偽りに集まる
People gather for falsehoods
嘘が欲しい本能
The instinct that wants lies
撮れてないみたい
It doesn't seem to be recorded
メイク・チョー
Make sure
Hah! Oh my God! That was so much fun!
I sang so many songs!
や、いっぱい歌っちゃったね。
Yeah, I sang so many songs.
ゲストのみなさんたちともね、歌っちゃいましたけれども。
I even sang together with all the guests.
みんなお気に入りとかある？
Does everyone have a favorite?
どうだった？
How was it?
How was it? How was all the performances?
If you guys have any favorite,
post with the hashtag: #CuriousTune3D.
Tell me your favorite or memorable moments
from the 3D birthday live! Yippee!
Oh my goodness!
Now it's announcement time!
Ada ads ya guys, no skipping ads ya guys.
There will be ads, guys, so no skipping ads.
Habis ini akan ada ads, jadi no skipping ya, okay?
After this there will be ads, so no skipping, okay?
Don't skip the ads, okay?
Oh my god.
The first one is...
Oh my god!
誕生日記念 2025年の
Birthday Celebration 2025
グッズだって！
merchandise!
The first one is this beautiful,
you know, this beautiful birthday merchandises.
Yes, that's right. We will be having 2025,
Anya Melfissa merchandises. Yippee!
Ada birthday 2025 merchandise guys, yippee!
There's birthday 2025 merchandise, guys, yippee!
Ini art-nya, art-nya gila keren banget
This art, the art is crazy cool,
nggak sih guys? Oh my god!
don't you think, guys? Oh my god!
ね、イラストめっちゃすごくない？
Hey, isn't the illustration amazing?
ね？
Right?
こちらの素敵なグッズのキービジュアルはね、
The key visual for these wonderful goods
SOLANI先生が担当してくださいました。
was created by SOLANI-sensei.
すごく素敵なイラストで私もお気に入りです。
It's a very wonderful illustration and my favorite too.
Aku suka banget sama illustration kali ini,
I really like the illustration this time,
gila keren banget, Anya banget nggak sih?
it's crazy cool, it's so "Anya," isn't it?
てことでね、Let's take a...
So, let's take a...
look at each item one by one, shall we?
Let's look at them!
The first one is this... Rubber Mat!
Rubber mat with the key visual!
Rubber mat pakai key visual yang tadi ya guys.
Rubber mat using the key visual from before, guys.
Yes, keren banget, oh my god!
Yes, it's so cool, oh my god!
ね、キービジュアルがプリントされた
See, it's a rubber mat printed
ラバーマットです。
with the key visual.
Ini bisa dipakai buat meja-meja nggak apa-apa,
You can use this for your desk, it's fine,
buat main board game gitu juga nggak apa-apa.
or for playing board games, that's also fine.
Terus buat main catur juga nggak apa-apa.
Then playing chess is also fine.
Dibuat tidur juga nggak apa-apa, guys.
Using it to sleep on is also fine, guys.
Ya, terserah ya guys. Dibuat tidur nggak apa-apa.
Well, it's up to you, guys. Sleeping on it is fine.
You can use this rubber mat anywhere you like.
And then, the next one...
The next merchandise, Acrylic Diorama Stand!
アクリルジオラマスタンドです。
It's an acrylic diorama stand.
This isn't your usual acrylic stand by the way.
It's made with three layers, for a dynamic,
three-dimensional look, guys. Oh my goodness!
Ini bukan acrylic stand biasa guys, ada tiga lapis
This isn't a normal acrylic stand guys, three layers
yang bikin tampilannya kelihatan lebih hidup.
that make it look more alive.
Kayak aku, kan keris hidup ya guys. Cocok banget?
Like me, I'm a "living Kris," guys. Doesn't it fit?
The illustration comes with a design frame.
ね、イラストにデザインフレームがついた
See, it comes with a design frame
ディスプレイにぴったりの商品です。
that makes it perfect for display.
Cocok banget buat display pokoknya guys.
It's perfect for display, guys.
Place it on your desk next to the rubber mat.
Taruh di meja kalian sama rubber mat juga bisa.
You can put it on your desk with the rubber mat.
Terus, ya... dibuat dimakan juga bisa, guys.
And, well... you can also eat it, guys.
Dimakan juga sebenarnya bisa, aduh.
Actually you can eat it, gosh.
Biasalah adrenalin habis live, ngomongnya aneh.
It's just post-live adrenaline, I'm talking weird.
Okay, the next merchandise. Let's take a look.
So cute! Look at this!
It's an Acrylic Keychain...
of general outfit Anya.
や、通常衣装のアクリルキーホルダーです。
Yeah, it's an acrylic keychain of my regular outfit.
めっちゃ可愛くない？
Isn't it super cute?
Yeah, me in my regular outfit.
So cute, mini Anya.
You can take it anywhere, guys. On your bag!
Di tas juga bisa. Terus diapain lagi ya?
On your bag also works. What else?
Di dompet...
On your wallet...
...bisa,
...can be.
di dompet juga bisa,
It can also go in your wallet,
terserah deh di mana aja, guys.
wherever you want, guys.
ねえ、お出かけとかにぜひ使ってください！
Please take it with you when you go out!
ということで、
With that said,
次はこちらです！
here is the next one!
こちらです！
Here it is!
可愛い！可愛くない？
So cute! Isn't it cute?
可愛いとかっこいいが
A blend of cute and cool,
混ざり合ってる
it's a...
ハンドミラーです。
...hand mirror.
The hand mirror has a chic design,
perfect for using at home or taking it with you
when you're out.
It's both stylish
and really easy to use.
Ini kacanya gila stylish banget, guys.
This mirror is insanely stylish, guys.
Terus ada kayak motif-motif Anya gitu
And it has these Anya-like motifs
di belakangnya kayak gini nih, guys.
on the back like this, guys.
Keren banget enggak sih? Oh my god.
It's so cool, isn't it? Oh my god.
Ini perfect banget kalau kalian mau keluar,
This is perfect if you want to go out,
terus ya biasanya untuk yang butuh kaca lah ya, guys. Daripada pakai HP, mending pakai hand mirror-nya Anya Melfissa. Ya enggak sih?
and usually for those who need a mirror. Rather than using your phone, it's better to use Anya Melfissa's hand mirror. Right?
シックなデザインのハンドミラーなので、
It's a hand mirror with a chic design,
家で使ってもよし、お外で使ってもよしな
so it's great for use at home or out and about.
使いやすいミラーとなっています。
It's a very easy-to-use mirror.
Di rumah juga boleh, guys.
You can use it at home too, guys.
Di rumah, di luar, terserah kalian, oke?
At home, outside, it's up to you, okay?
Next up! Next up is this!
VOICE PACK! Oh my god, yes!
Voice pack, and this time the script is written
by yours truly, Anya Melfissa,
just like pretty much every year.
Every year, I... I write my own birthday voice pack.
ねえ、こちらの台本、また今年もね、また、ええ、
I wrote the script again this year,
アーニャ・メルフィッサです。台本担当、アーニャ・メルフィッサです。
I, Anya Melfissa, am in charge of the script.
よろしくお願いします。毎年ながらの、はい。
Please look forward to it. As I do every year.
And of course,
there are also special bonuses you get
for buying the merchandise set.
Here are the bonuses.
Postcard with a duplicate foil-stamped autograph!
Yeah, duplicate autograph means,
the autograph is, you know, foil-stamped.
Tanda tangannya jadi kayak dicetak pakai foil stamping ya, guys.
The signature is printed using foil stamping, guys.
And don't worry, it's not a limited edition this time,
so everyone can get one.
Bukan limited edition, guys, jadi, oh my god, beli sih.
It's not limited edition, guys, so please buy it.
Sudah enggak limited masa enggak beli? Iya enggak?
Since it's not limited, you have to buy it, right?
Sudah dibuat enggak limited masa enggak beli, guys?
I made it non-limited, so why wouldn't you buy it?
Gila, keterlaluan banget sih.
That would be just too much.
Keterlaluan banget.
Way too much.
And then the next bonus...
The next bonus is...
The voice pack...
the voice pack translations! Yes!
I forgot to mention, my voice pack is only available in, you know, in Japanese.
So, if you guys get the bonus,
one of them is actually English and Bahasa Indonesia script
of my voice pack.
Jadi, voice pack-nya cuma ada bahasa Jepang, tapi tenang aja, guys,
The voice pack is only in Japanese, but don't worry,
bonusnya ada translation Bahasa Indonesia
the bonus includes Indonesian
sama translation Bahasa Inggris juga.
and English translations as well.
Jadi tunggu apa lagi? Tunggu apa lagi?
So what are you waiting for? What are you waiting for?
ねえ、こちらなんとね、あの、ボイスはね、あの、毎年ながら日本語なんですけれども、
The voice pack is in Japanese as usual,
こちらボーナスとして、英語とインドネシア語の台本も付くので、
but as a bonus, we've included English and Indonesian scripts,
ぜひ皆さん楽しんでください。
so please enjoy it,
いろんな言語でね。
in various languages.
ということで、次！こちらです！
With that, next! Here it is!
Yay! Special bonus!
If you buy the merchandise set, you'll get a special card
that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game release last September!
Oh my god!
Buat teman-temannya yang beli set komplit merchandise kali ini,
For those of you who buy the complete merch set,
kalian bakal dapat satu kartu yang bisa dipakai di Hololive Official Card Game
you'll get a card for the Hololive Official Card Game
yang rilis September tahun lalu, guys.
that was released last September, guys.
ねえ、今回グッズセットをご購入いただいた方に、
Those who purchase the merch set this time,
あの、昨年9月に発売されたホロライブ公式カードゲームで使用できるカードが
will receive a card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game
1枚特典として付きます！
that was released last September!
いや、この特典、めっちゃ良くない？
Isn't this bonus amazing?
ねえ、みんなTCG好きなんだよね？
Everyone loves TCGs, right?
いや、楽しそうだな、ってずっと思ってるのね、アーニャも。
Anya also thinks they look really fun.
いつか私もやりたいなと思います。
I want to try playing it someday.
It's an Oshi Holomem card by the way.
Yeah, your key card to show off...
...of your fave.
Kartu ini itu oshi holo mem card gitu guys.
This card is like an oshi Holomem card, guys.
For details about the card and how to play, please check the website!
ね、カードの詳細や遊び方についてはね、
So, regarding the details and how to play the card,
ホームページで確認してくださいね。
please check the homepage!
Also the card will be available in Japanese only by the way.
日本語、日本語のみですね、カードの方は。
As for the card, it will only be in Japanese.
This bonus by the way is only valid for purchases made at hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP.
Jadi em, ini bonusnya itu cuma untuk kalian
So, um, this bonus is only for those of you...
yang beli di hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP ya guys.
...who buy at the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP, guys.
And there's a second announcement as well!
We still have announcements! Oh my goodness!
ね、こちらね、あの... 次の告知、
So, this is, um... the next announcement,
次のお知らせなんですけれども、
the next notice, but...
なんと！
Believe it or not!
オリ曲のMVが出ます！
A music video for my original song is coming out!
オリ曲のMVがね、なんと、今日のこの後
The original song MV, amazingly, will be...
22時でね、あのプレミア公開なので楽しみにしいておいてください！
...premiering today at 10 PM, so please look forward to it!
MV ori song MV guys! Habis ini jam 8 ya guys!
MV original song MV, guys! It's at 8 o'clock after this, guys!
Jam 8 malam Waktu Indonesia Barat habis ini!
8 PM Western Indonesia Time, after this!
The MV of my original song will be released at 10 PM JST after this, after this live!
It'll also be released on various music distribution services from, you know,
from 12 AM your time zone.
So please look forward to it!
Yippee!
各種音楽配信サービスにもね、リリースされるので
It will also be released on various music distribution services...
お楽しみにしいておいてください！
...so please look forward to it!
そしてですね、
And then,
次が最後の曲になるんですけれども、
the next one will be the last song.
ね、みんな楽しみに、きっと楽しみにしていた
The song that everyone has surely been looking forward to...
あの曲を歌います！
...I'm going to sing that song!
The next song is gonna be the last song.
Sad, but you guys will love this performance! I'll do my best!
Okay! Onto the last song then!
My new original song...
CHRONIC
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey
Walking round' in reality, I'm so done, done
Feel like I'm losing my gravity, my vision
Of you that I see clearly in my mind
I'm so you
My thoughts collide in my mind, I know I really should try
To think, to think on my own, but oh
We're tied together, it's true
I think I'm becoming you
Don't blink, don't blink, I, I, they're asking who
Took me so far away, far away
Digitally recreate everything
I, I...
I wanna show you why I
(Parallel we rise)
Love it, chk-chk-boom
Chronic, chronic, chronic, collide 'til we go atomic
Turn it, turn it, turn it to a different space, different wave
Want it, want it, want it, opposites go supersonic
Love it, love it, love it, dive into the fate we made
Sometimes I think you're here, yeah, you're my only one
You make it feel so real, outside it's so bizarre
Devastation and creation, ooh
I'll be your shooting star
A new perspective of life while I just try to survive
I know, I know, we're not going down
I guess I can't compromise the in-between of our lives
I know, I know, I, I, you must be who
Took me so far away, far away
Digitally recreate everything
I, I...
I wanna show you why I
(Parallel we rise)
Love it, chk-chk-boom
Chronic, chronic, chronic, collide 'til we go atomic
Turn it, turn it, turn it to a different space, different wave
Want it, want it, want it, opposites go supersonic
Love it, love it, love it, dive into the fate we made
Whisper...
Come take me right away
Whisper, whisper, whisper
Merging right into you all night
Me and my only...
Press and hold onto continue
It'll always be you
Tell me you won't go away
Imagining maybe one day
That we'll meet in between
Organic life and blue screens
I, I do need you
Mirror on the wall say
You'll take me so far
Chronic, chronic, chronic
Collide 'til we go atomic
Turn it, turn it, turn it
To a different space, different wave
Want it, want it, want it
Opposites go supersonic
Love it, love it, love it
Dive into the fate we made
Whisper, whisper, whisper
Come take me right away
Merging right into you all night
Whisper, whisper, whisper
Me and my only...
Press and hold onto continue
It'll always be you
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
あ、はい！
Ah, yes!
Through the Curious Tune
Anya Melfissa Birthday Live 2025